Let me show you a video. Trigger
warning. It's of Margaret Thatcher.
>> Where there is discord, may we bring
harmony. Where there is error, may we
bring truth. Where there is doubt, may
we bring faith. And where [snorts] there
is despair, may we bring hope.
>> This is Margaret Thatcher about to enter
10 Downing Street for the first time as
prime minister of the United Kingdom
[music] in May 1979. If you can hear it
above the crowd, she's opted to quote
from the so-called prayer of Francis of
Aisi. [music]
better known in its setting to music as
the hymn Make Me a Channel of Your
Peace.
[music]
>> Also featured in the hit musical Come
From Away. Thatcher opted not to mention
the peace bit, which might be for the
best. Because if there was one key event
which held Thatcher's premiership in
place, it wasn't peace, but war. His
Margaret Thatcher on a tank.
See, Thatcher's time in office didn't
start off all that well. Her government
was really keen to cut inflation and in
order to do so chose to hike interest
rates to an incredible 17%.
This was a period where most Brits had
variable rate mortgages which meant that
homeowners monthly repayments briefly
spiked in an incident of exceptionally
brief hardship which British uncles
still talk about as though they were
victims of some kind of war crime. The
country fell into a recession and the
number of people out of work surpassed
three million for the first time since
the 1930s.
[applause]
[cheering]
>> Through all this, Thatcher's popularity
cratered. [snorts]
Immediately after delivering that poem
from France Visi, she'd boasted a net
approval rating of plus two. By the end
of 1981, a year which had involved
widespread rioting in Liverpool,
Manchester and London, and the premiere
of the less good musical Cats, that had
dropped to minus 41. Then something
happened which was to change all of
that.
>> ARGENTINIANS COME.
>> ON THE MORNING OF THE 2nd of April 1982,
630 troops from the Argentine military
landed on and swiftly rested control of
the Forkland Islands. The small
archipelago in the South Atlantic had
been under continuous British
administration since the 1830s, although
Argentina had long claimed the islands,
too. Argentina itself had been under a
military dictatorship since 1976,
and the government's campaign of
violence against its own people had led
to civil unrest. Argentina's leader,
Galatieri, thus made the decision to
seize the islands in an attempt to rally
some support behind himself and his
regime.
The Argentinians hadn't expected Britain
to respond, believing the islands to be
too far away and too unimportant to be
worth defending. Some of Thatcher's
government felt simile.
She didn't. Thatcher dispatched a task
force of 127 ships, including a nuclear
submarine, to retake the islands. Over
74 days, the British armed forces fought
to [music] retake them. 255 British and
649 Argentine soldiers died before
General Mario Mendez surrendered on the
14th of June.
Goutieri, who had only initiated the
invasion in pursuit of popularity, was
removed from power and the military
dictatorship collapsed not long after.
Thatcher on the other hand, a poll
carried out in June 1982 recorded an
approval rate of plus 23, a jump of more
than 50 percentage points from 18 months
before. From being at risk of being
ousted by her enemies within the Tory
party, she went on to win two more
elections and become the longest serving
prime minister in modern British
history. War, it seems, can sometimes be
pretty good for embattled politicians.
Whatever drawbacks it might have in
terms of casualties and cost, it can
provide a means of drumming up support
where previously little existed. On an
unrelated note, Donald Trump keeps
threatening to invade places.
>> My proudest legacy will be that of a
peacemaker and unifier. That's what I
want to be, a peacemaker and a unifier.
>> This is Donald Trump delivering his
second inaugural address in January
2025. Trump had talked about wanting to
be a quote unquote peacemaker a lot on
[music] the campaign trail.
>> I will prevent and very easily World War
II. Very easily.
>> He professed to be able to end the war
in Ukraine in just 24 hours and humbly
told voters in Michigan that he was the
candidate of peace.
>> I am the candidate of peace. I am peace.
>> He actually says, "I am peace." Which is
fantastic line. It's the Democrats. He
told voters who are the wararmongers he
was the man who was going to end the
so-called forever wars.
>> They said he will start a war. I'm not
going to start a war. I'm going to stop
wars.
>> Immediately after getting into office,
he set his heart on transforming this
apparent love of peace into a Nobel
Peace Prize. [music] Going on what can
only be described as a for your
consideration campaign for the award in
which he repeatedly claimed to have
ended eight conflicts.
>> Everyone says that I should get the
Nobel Peace Prize for each one of these
achievements. He was snubbed by the
academy.
>> No, I don't care about the Nobel Prize.
>> In the end, he had to settle for a FIFA
peace prize at a weird ceremony which
was a kind of Avengers Endgame for
corruption. Unfortunately for him,
Trump's second time in office didn't
start well. Over the course of his first
year back in power, the US was gripped
by an affordability crisis in which,
despite headline inflation rates
remaining relatively low, Americans
struggled with the high cost of housing,
healthcare, energy, and eggs. His brutal
attempts to address perceived illegal
immigration through setting barely
trained ICE agents loose on the streets
of American cities was not the vote
winner he thought it might be. All the
while, the Epstein files, in which Trump
definitely isn't massively implicated,
constantly threatened to drop.
>> President Trump did nothing wrong. And
what President Trump has always said is
that he was from Palm Beach and so is
Jeffrey Epstein. Trump managed to hold
on to a positive approval level for less
than two months before sentiment began
to float ever downward. A year in, he
turned a plus two net approval rate into
minus9,
which is presumably why he decided to
try and do something to change all of
that.
>> Happy New Year.
>> In September 2025, Donald Trump
announced that he was renaming the US
Department of Defense the Department of
War. a return to the name that the
department had held until 1947. It
quickly became clear that he meant it or
kind of. The period since has been
witnessed to an avalanche of not quite
war mongering by Trump and his allies.
There were the air strikes on apparent
drug smuggling vessels in the Caribbean.
There was the bombastic attack on
Caracus and seizure of Nicholas Majurro.
There was the announcement of the Donro
doctrine and the intention to hold full
control over what Marco Rubio called our
hemisphere.
>> This is the Western Hemisphere. This is
where we live and we're not going to
allow the Western Hemisphere to be a
base of operation for adversaries,
competitors, and rivals of the United
States.
>> There were the follow-up threats to
Cuba, Colombia, and Mexico.
>> Cubid looks like it's ready to fall.
>> Things really reached ahead with the
will he, won't he? hints at potentially
seizing Greenland from Denmark, which is
supposed to be an ally. Then, when that
turned out to be the equivalent of
dropping a turd on the international
stage, he turned his attention to Iran.
>> We're watching Iran. We're watching
Iran. You know, we have a lot of ships
going that direction just in case.
>> Like, there's probably been at least one
more thing since we filmed this. It's
been a lot. Donald Trump's path from
peacemaker to wararmonger has not been
the same as Margaret Thatcher's.
Thatcher was in a way lucky. The
Falklands happened to her. Trump, by
contrast, has consistently been the
instigator of his conflicts. Their needs
in the moment of war, however, are not
dissimilar. Here are two leaders elected
on radical manifestos who nonetheless
quickly found themselves [music]
deeply unpopular, even among many on
their own side.
>> ICE, DHS, Christine, have been a
political disaster. two leaders in
desperate need of something to change
the narrative. Two leaders wanting to
unite their countries behind them. To
say that Donald Trump might be using
war, at least partly as a means to
achieve a similar turnaround in domestic
support, however, seems kind of obvious.
If you've not worked that one out for
yourself already, there are plenty of
commentators willing to tell you [music]
that. What I've become more and more
interested in over the past few months,
however, is the extent to which similar
patterns appear to be repeating across
the world. Across continents and across
the political spectrum, we have found
ourselves in a world of deeply unpopular
[music] leaders. Some of them have
sought out war. Others decry it, but
have nevertheless succumbed to the
emergence of a world of rearmament and
remobilization. is a world of disliked
and disconnected leaders marching us
towards war. And maybe less importantly,
would it actually serve to make any of
them any more popular? It marks the
return of the RAF to nuclear deterrence
for the first time in three decades,
representing the biggest strengthening
of our deterrence posture in a
generation.
>> It's not just Trump. Rearmament and
heightened military rhetoric is very
much the theme of our age.
There are of course the obvious
examples. Vladimir Putin and Benjamin
Netanyahu were among the earliest
adopters of this new international logic
which might always equals right. Neither
the invasion of Ukraine nor the genocide
in Gaza were unprecedented. They both
represented attempts to achieve
longstanding national desires and settle
long-standing national scores. What was
different was the sheer scale of
military force used to do so.
This has required a complete reshaping
of both countries economies. Russia's
military spending has increased by 126%
since 2020. Spending on the military and
police currently accounts for around 38%
of total government spending. Israel's
destruction of Gaza has involved similar
shifts. The mobilization of reserveists
has led to regular labor shortages in
peaceime industries, even as hefty
salaries for those fighting has kept the
economy looking pretty healthy. Now,
it's turning to African countries to
plug the gap. More than 200 farm workers
left Malawi for Israel last month
following a secret deal with the
government. Neither country has simply
gone to war. They have to an even
greater extent than before placed
conflict at the core of their economies,
diplomatic relationships and national
identities. Regarding the new sanctions,
first of all, there is nothing new here.
Yes, they are of a serious nature for
us. Of course, this is understandable
and they will have certain consequences,
but still they will not significantly
affect our economic well-being.
>> The region which I think is most
revealing of the way the world is
headed, however, is Western Europe.
Surprise, I think the place where I live
is most interesting. [snorts] Really
like really fortunate coincidence. We
are used to politicians with a sort of
moral vision of taking us towards utopia
grounded on values which are either
religious values um or our
straightforward traditional postmarxist
socialist values. Now that kind of
vision politics is alien to Karma.
>> For all he likes to talk about
missiondriven government, his government
has lacked a unifying mission. Heck,
I've made that argument on this very
channel. You keep saying that your
mission is growth. or sometimes national
renewal, whatever that means. But that's
a bit like saying that my business makes
profit. Growth is an outcome. It's not a
mission. And yet, amid all of this
flip-flopping, there is a set of
policies on which Starma has remained
steadfastly consistent. Kistama is a
prime minister of rearmament. More than
anything else, his government has been
one of preparing for war. The manifesto
on which the Labour Party was elected
back in 2024 included in it a pledge to
set out the path to spending 2.5% of GDP
on defense. Sama has since promised to
speed up his ambitions here, aiming to
achieve this as soon as 2027. He's also
said that that target should increase to
3% should the Labour Party win the next
election. Simply incredible to not be
able to believe in the prospect of world
peace, but to be able to believe that
the Labour Party is going to win the
next election. The cash being diverted
to the British armed forces at the
moment is according to the prime
minister's office the biggest sustained
increase in defense spending since the
Cold War, which might sound like just
one policy announcement among many. But
once you begin to notice it, you realize
quite how central the military has
become to [music] everything the current
UK government does. Want to boost
economic growth outside of London? How
about the armed forces? Want to create
jobs? How about the armed forces? want
to develop alternative forms of training
for young people who don't want to go to
university. How about the armed forces?
This last announcement was explicitly
framed as a response to a call by the
UK's chief of the defense staff for a
whole of society approach to defense to
foster skills and opportunities for our
young people and foster a sense of
national pride and purpose that has
characterized our nation in times of
conflict.
>> Kind of chilling. We're not just looking
at isolated recruitment programs or
purchases of military hardware here. We
too are staring down a desire to reenter
our entire economy and society around
war.
>> We are moving to war fighting readiness
as the central purpose of our armed
forces.
>> This approach is echoing across Western
European nations. Since 2023, EU leaders
have regularly talked about needing to
shift the continent into war economy
mode. German Chancellor Friedrich Mertz
is currently on a mission to build the
strongest conventional army in Europe,
paid for with billions of euros worth of
borrowing. France's new army chief of
staff suggested in November that the
country needed to be ready to lose its
children.
The motivations of Star Merz and Macron
are evidently not the same as those of
Putin or Nanyahu or even Trump. Europe's
rearmament has much more in common with
Thatcher than with Galieri. It is
reactive. Even if military leaders are
clearly motivated to say shocking things
and to overstate various threats in
order to convince politicians to buy
them new toys, let's not pretend that
there isn't some logic to this
rearmament in an age of obligerent
Russia and a chaotic US.
>> All the United States is asking for is a
place called Greenland. And yet I do
think it's worth poking into the level
of enthusiasm with which Starmer Mertron
and other Western European leaders have
thrown themselves into this real life
game of risk because there is something
which all of these leaders do have in
common with Trump and Netanyahu if not
Putin. All of the leaders who have been
the most vocal about the need to be
ready for war are also deeply unpopular.
>> Oh dear, you couldn't make this up. A
new poll has revealed that Zakista is
the least popular prime minister on
record [music] and Rachel Reeves is the
least popular chancellor since their
records began.
>> I need to start this section by showing
you perhaps the worst video I've ever
seen and I have to watch my own loads of
times.
>> This is the tale of two.
>> This has nearly a million views. Known
across the land as the Granny Farmer, a
soulless little man who betrayed the
farmer.
[music]
[sighs]
>> Forget under 16. I think you need to ban
social media for over 50. It's again not
just Kiss Dharma or Donald Trump. We
live in an age of unpopular leaders,
which sounds sensationalist or
subjective. It sounds like I'm just
telling you that I happen not to like
many of today's world leaders, but it is
a matter of record that over the past
decade, the very act of being a
politician in power has become something
which makes politicians unpopular.
>> This has been a massive turnaround
throughout the relatively short history
of popular democracy. It's generally
been the case that one of the best
things you can do if you want to win an
election is to already hold the office
that you're seeking. Unless you've
really screwed things up, winning
re-election has almost always been
easier than being a challenger
candidate. There's a name for this, the
incumbency effect, named for the manner
in which it favors the incumbent
candidate. And you can see it IN THE
RESULTS. FOUR YEARS. FOUR MORE YEARS.
>> Here in the UK, once a political party
has won a single general election,
they've tended to hold on for a few
more. American presidents who stand for
re-election have tended to be voted back
in for another go at things. There are
several potential explanations for this.
Some of it is likely just down to voters
simply being more familiar with the
existing president, prime minister, or
other representative. Particularly in
elections for local representatives, a
challenger candidate might literally
just be a name that you've never heard
before on a ballot paper. You might have
no idea who they are. An existing MP or
Congress person, however, is more likely
to be a fully fleshed out person that
you've seen on TV or at events with a
face, a family, pets, a personality.
>> This time, he's the lesser of two evils.
More than this, you've probably seen a
candidate seeking re-election on TV or
at an event in their capacity as that
elected official. Everything a
politician does in their job is
basically a campaign ad for the next
election. They're in the White House or
on an aircraft carrier or at the UN. If
part of deciding who to vote for is
considering whether a candidate could
fulfill the basic requirements of the
job, we don't have to do as much
considering for an incumbent. We've
already seen them doing it and it has
generally been the case in the past that
people have found that reassuring
>> to protect our rights to make sure that
everyone in this country is treated
equally and that everyone is given a
fair shot at making it.
>> Finally, being in office comes with a
whole load of time that you can use for
promoting yourself and perhaps more
crucially in countries like the US where
money plays an outsized role in
politics, [music] fundrais. Someone who
is running for office while working
another job isn't going to be able to
spend as much time campaigning and
speaking with donors as someone whose
life is dedicated [music] to politics.
The size of the incumbency advantage can
vary wildly across constituencies,
districts, time, and parties from as
little as a few percentage points to as
much as 15%.
for this reason that political parties
can be willing to field frankly ancient
candidates when that seems farical. In
>> 1948, twothirds of Americans
said America [clears throat]
and Western European friends
should join together.
>> Over the past few years, however, cracks
have begun to show in this once ironclad
rule of politics. 2024 was a pretty big
year for elections, the biggest ever in
human history. Half the world's
population had the opportunity to vote
across 72 countries. And the result was
an absolute drubbing for incumbents.
Donald Trump's defeat of Kla Harris
marked the third time in a row that
America's incumbent party had lost the
presidency. The UK's Conservative Party
experienced its worst defeat since 1832.
Emanuel Macron called a snap election
only for his ensemble coalition to lose
almost a third of its seats amid a
squeeze from right and left.
>> It reminds you of that quote from
Charles de Gaulle. You know, how can
anyone govern a country with 246
different types of cheese?
>> Japan's all powerful Liberal Democratic
Party suffered the second worst results
in [music] its history was forced to
form a minority coalition. The African
National Congress, which similarly has
governed South Africa consistently since
the end of apartheid, lost its majority
for the first time in decades and also
had to form a coalition. Modi's
multi-party national democracy alliance
was also pushed into a coalition where
they' previously governed independently.
[music]
Each leader's defeat was preaged by
particular local events, scandals, and
trends. And yet, the overall takeaway
from that year of elections was clear.
Being in power has itself become
unpopular. We have, as the meme would
have it, become ungovernable.
>> I won't do what you tell me. Perhaps the
weirdest aspect of all of this is that
the various quirks present in many of
these countries electoral systems means
that many leaders who have lost ground
recently have still managed to cling on
to power. Emanuel Macron is still the
president of France despite having a net
approval of minus 63. How can anyone
govern a country with 246 different
types of cheese? Elsewhere, politicians
who have won have quickly become
unpopular, partly because they happened
to win. Donald Trump and Kstarma are
just the most obvious examples here.
Elsewhere across Europe, a 2025 Yugov
poll found that Germany's Mertz, Italy's
Maloney, Spain Sanchez, and Denmark's
Friedrien to all have net negative
approval ratings. In an age of rage,
it's easy to be swept into power in
anti-establishment anger. But as soon as
you cross the threshold of the seat of
power, you'd better be ready for that
anger to turn on you. The question which
remains then is whether this widespread
current propensity for us to turn on our
leaders is making them more likely to
take us to war.
>> We shall defend our island, whatever the
cost may be. We shall fight on beaches,
landing grounds, in fields, in streets,
and on the hills.
>> Academics refer to the idea that
politicians might sometimes use foreign
wars to distract from domestic failures
as the diversionary theory of war. To
quote Jarus Lavia, this posits that
under conditions such as economic
adversity or political unrest, the
country's leader may attempt to generate
a foreign policy crisis in order both to
divert domestic discontent and bolster
their political fortunes through a rally
around the flag effect. The rally around
the flag effect here refers to the
theory that in times of external
conflict, citizens tend to embrace an
ingroup outgroup mindset. The result is
that internal divisions between
different social groups within a country
fade as people turn their eye towards
the enemy instead. In this formulation,
then the diversionary theory of war
posits that an unpopular leader might
start a conflict in order to co-opt
those effects and to break down any
division between themselves and the
people that they govern, thereby
boosting their popularity.
>> I'm doing my part. What's interesting is
that academic studies around
diversionary uses of war tend to raise
more questions than they answer. At the
most basic level, there's a massive
question mark over how successful
diversionary wars or military action is
at actually shoring up support from
popular leaders. For every Margaret
Thatcher, there's a goutier. For every
Putin, there's a George W. Bush or Tony
Blair. Both of whose popularities were
ultimately harmed, not helped by the
Iraq war. When you arrive into a a
situation like this, a live television
interview, and you come through the
gates and you have people chanting with
the black cards and so on, and they're
shouting war criminal, and they're
shouting at you. Are you a war criminal?
>> Of course, I don't believe that. But
>> why do they why are they calling you
one?
>> Ryan, you know why they are. And and
look, I'm not going to explain it. I
don't have to explain it. They can
explain it. Other scholars have
questioned how common uses of the tactic
actually are, crunching huge piles of
data to try and assess whether there is
a statistical relationship between civil
unrest within a country and the
likelihood that that country ends up
going to war. Most enlightening for any
discussion of today's shift towards
rearmament, however, is this paper by
Kyle Haynes published in 2015. Haynes
argues that diversionary military action
is very much a tactic which unpopular
leaders use in pursuit of a turnaround
in public affections. And yet rather
than a rally around the flag approach,
he suggests that the real motivation is
often a desire on the part of failing
leaders to perform competence. This
makes more and more sense the more you
think about it. For one, extremely
unpopular leaders usually aren't viewed
as merely evil. Real unpopularity only
comes with the stench of incompetence.
Thatcher and Galtieri both received
plenty of criticism for how they treated
their own citizens, but it was a sense
that they just weren't very good at
their jobs, which was the real killer.
Controversial actions might deepen the
extent to which existing opponents
dislike a leader, but it's being viewed
as incompetent, which risks losing the
backing of your most loyal supporters.
Looking across today's unpopular
premers, it's clear that a lot separates
them. There is a clear blue water
between the politics of Kistama and that
of Donald Trump. More than anything, one
has actively sought to start conflicts
where the other's military maneuvering
has been more responsive. What unites
them is a complete inability not to step
on rakes. Trump almost talked his way
into having to release Epstein files in
which, again, he's clearly not
implicated at all. Then he began
subjecting the country to his ice goons
who more than just evil and violent are
also completely inept. Starmmer's
reverse Mida's touch is such that he has
the ability to take extremely popular
policies, announce them and somehow make
them unpopular. And yet war, war comes
heaped with connotations of competence.
Competence and war are often seen to go
hand in hand in our culture. Take a
baracab. If I were to ask you to think
of the two most iconic moments of Barack
Obama's presidency, it's highly likely
you'll either land on this photo or this
moment.
>> Tonight, I can report to the American
people and to the world that the United
States has conducted an operation that
killed Osama bin Laden, the leader of
al-Qaeda.
>> Once upon a time, the Affordable Care
Act might have also loomed large. Or
Georgia behind the camera is dead set on
the tanned suit being the most iconic
moment. But it's the military action
which is really stuck across the whole
culture which is real real Fox News real
Fox News energy to that [laughter]
like I remember the terror war is often
what we think that leaders do. There's a
phrase which gets thrown around in
British politics a lot that the first
duty of government is the defense of the
realm which let's be honest pretty
cringe. You're not King Arthur, you did
PPE at Oxford. But it underlines a
cultural trope in which we are minded to
think of a leader as being more of a
leader if they lead through a conflict.
And that trope is in many regards just
as dangerous to the world at the moment
as the more bombastic adventures of
Donald Trump.
>> Let's be cleareyed about where this
leads.
A world of fortresses will be poorer,
more fragile, [music]
and less sustainable.
>> This is Mark Khan delivering his special
address to the World Economic Forum in
Davos this January. The speech mourned
the arrival of an era in which great
powers seek to get their own way through
military might and stressed the role
that so-called middle powers might play
in this new world order.
>> Middle powers must act together because
if we're not at the table, we're on the
menu.
>> We could talk for days about how the
domestic performance of Donald Trump is
or isn't guiding his foreign military
adventures. And yet, to my mind, [music]
it's at the level of these middle
powers, well, at least not superpowers,
where the conversation about unpopular
leaders and war becomes most
interesting, which again, you know,
probably not uninfluenced by the fact
that I live in the UK. Carney also took
a moment to talk about his government's
plans to throw money at the military and
place rearmorament at the heart of the
economy.
>> We're doubling our defense spending by
the end of this decade, and we're doing
so in ways that build our domestic
industries. Nevertheless, Carney is
unique among the leaders that we've
talked about in today's video in that he
actually is pretty popular. He's
consistently had a net positive approval
during his time in office so far with
this Davos speech boosting it as high as
26% which at our present juncture is
just wildly popular. As we've seen
across other G7 and middle power
countries, political leaders have become
systematically unloved. And facing such
unpopularity, it's no surprise that they
might turn to grandstanding on the
international stage. One of the least
derogatory nicknames that Kristama has
gained over his first two years in power
is never here. A reference to the fact
that he always seems to be off on a
journ somewhere. Ukraine, the G20, the
US. But can you blame him? Like
everything he touches in the UK seems to
turn to [__] other politicians wants to
take on his leadership and his
popularity only seems to fool and fool
on a level of sheer mental
self-preservation. I would also prefer
to just go and hang out with Macron and
Mertz and talk about Ukraine. As the
example of Ukraine shows, there are
logical reasons for some of the shifts
towards militarism. An expansionist
Russia, an expansionist US, and an
unpredictable China. Yet, that doesn't
always mean that the responses are
commensurate with the threat. I
mentioned in my recent video about
nuclear warfare, the UK's plan to
acquire a bunch of F-35A fighter jets
capable of carrying tactical nuclear
bombs. A move with no upsides and the
downside of having the potential for
encouraging nuclear escalation. We're
about to spend almost a billion pounds
on these things. And I don't think it's
ridiculous to suggest that at least part
of that decision is rooted in a personal
effort by this guy and those around him
to not look like such a nerd. Whatever
actual reasons for arming up might
exist, a pandemic of unpopularity among
our leaders risks exacerbating an
already strange scenario. It is, for
what it's worth, unlikely to work.
There's only so long that you can tell
people that there's no money to build
houses or hospitals or splashing out on
fighter jets for a war which might not
come. And one risk is that it only leads
us into a cycle where unpopularity
pushes us closer and closer to the
brink. The theory that embattled leaders
might jump into military endeavors has
always been something which has long
been on the mind of North Korea
watchers. The fear is always that should
the regime ever come under threat, they
might just fire their nuclear arsenal at
Washington or somewhere. If you want to
find out a little bit more about the
founding of North Korea, then I can only
recommend going and checking out Mad
Kings, a new series by the team behind
Real Life Law, which looks at the lives
of various despots and dictators. From
Moamar Gaddafi and his all female
bodyguard unit to Kim Ilsung, who
remained North Korea's eternal president
despite having died all the way back in
1994. Who knows, maybe there'll be a
Donald Trump episode on that list at
some point in the future. But Nebula has
more than just despots and tyrants. I'm
currently enjoying Taramoon's
fascinating Nebula exclusive series
Politics, which explores the
politicization of boobs throughout
history, including in our new postwoke
era. Politics is a really fantastic
example of why Nebula is so great for
both audiences and creators. If Tara had
made politics for YouTube, I think we
all know the likelihood of it actually
turning up in anyone's recommendations
feeds. Nebula gives us the freedom to
make stuff for you without having to
worry about either recommendation or
monetization algorithms hiding it away.
More than that, in an era where YouTube
has become more and more clickbaity, our
goal with Nebula is to make a genuinely
prestige premium experience where you
can sit back on your sofa, whack some
stuff up on the TV, and actually find
something highquality and enriching to
watch without wasting millions of hours
scrolling through sloth. All of us
involved in creating Nebula are viewers
as well as creators, and we want it to
be a really high quality experience. If
you sign up to Nebula using my link
go.nebula.tv/tomicholas,
you'll get 50% off an annual plan,
bringing the price down to just $2.50
per month, which is an absolute steal.
Alongside being a fantastic package of
stuff to watch, signing up to Nebula
using my link, go.bula.tv/nicholas
TV/nicholas really helps to support my
work at a time when making videos for
the internet is becoming harder and
harder. Not only do we get paid more
every time someone watches our videos on
Nebula rather than on YouTube, I also
get a little kickback when you sign up,
which makes a huge difference in keeping
things ticking over. That link again is
go.nebula.tv/tomnicholas.
Thanks so much for watching once again
and I will see you over on Nebula. All
that's left for me to do is to say a
massive thank you to my top tier
supporters over on Patreon at
patreon.com/tomicholas
who are Richard Garry Dickon Spain, Bill
Mitchell, ZedC Ree, Zoe Alden, Alexander
Blank, Neil Zildgard, Sophia R, Sergio
Suarez, Richard Rapun, Gabriel Ko,
Fiasco Linguini, Agent Maxwell, Glenn
Sugdan, Emil Jarabar, Yillimson, Paulus
Edus, Sam Forinatu, Sandre Yaren,
Douglas Urquart, Ahmed Haric and Hasty.
If you want to join them in getting
early access to the videos, copies of
scripts to them, access to my weekly
blog where I tell you what we're up to,
and a bunch of other stuff, you can find
out how to do so at
patreon.com/tomnicholas.
Thanks so much for watching once again
and I'll see you in the next